kentbrushes.com 2016-10-07

# Cookies and Privacy Policy

Privacy

The policy which we employ when dealing with any personal information submitted via this website is outlined below. We aim to take every possible measure to protect your information at all times.

Definitions

“We” or “us” in terms of Data Protection, and your information, refers to G.B. Kent & Sons Plc. “Personal Information” refers to all data you enter into this website which identifies you, or which can be considered privileged, including but not limited to your email address.

Your Consent

By using this website, you agree to this privacy policy, and when you submit any of your details or personal information, you are agreeing that you accept the manner in which we state we will use those details.

Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may change our Privacy and Security policies from time to time – we are constantly reviewing them to ensure that our customers (and their customers) are protected to the best of our abilities. Please check this page regularly for any updates and changes.

What information do we collect?

Information may be collected when you use certain components of this website. Our own server – like all web servers – logs your visit including your Internet Protocol (IP) address and date and time of visit. All data is kept within the United Kingdom, and we never share this information with anyone unless compelled to do so by law.

We may collect, store and use the following kinds of personal data:

  * Information about your computer and about your visits to and use of this website (including your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit, pages viewed and activity on each page);
  * Should you send us an email via the contact form, your name, email address and message will be emailed to us (as you would expect). This information is kept private, your details will not be passed on to any third party. We will store this information within our own email system so that we are able to respond to you. Your details will not be added to our newsletter unless you specify you would specifically like to receive communication from us on anything other than the initial enquiry you made.
  * Should you comment on a blog post on this site, then your name, email address, IP address and message will be stored in our website database (as you would expect). This makes your name, website address and comment (but not your email address) viewable by the general public on the website.
  * If you sign up to receive our newsletter, your name and email address will be added to a newsletter system database. You may opt-out of our emails at any time. An ‘unsubscribe’ link is included in all of our email newsletters.

Cookies

The UK has now implemented (as of 26 May 2011) the EU e-Privacy directive that requires website owners to make users aware that their site uses cookies. While the ICO has not issued much in way of technical detail, what is clear is that they still expect website owners to take action to become compliant. Over the coming months we will be working on developing the best methods for us obtain your consent without it ruining your experience of our website.

What are cookies?

Cookies are small harmless text files placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the website. The Cookie acts as an identification card for the visiting site. They enable your browser to exchange information with the website server, and can be used for essential purposes (such as remembering you’ve logged in to a site or what product you have put into your shopping cart), or optional purposes (such as for website analytics purposes or how many visitors came to the site).

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit All About Cookies. However, please note that if you choose to disable cookies, then parts of this website may not function correctly and it will severely harm our business, we will no longer be able to track visits to our website, see what the most popular pages are or devices looking at our website, it will be the equivalent of running a sweet shop, blindfolded with no stock-taking facility available.

What cookies do we use?

The table below list the cookies we use and will set regardless of your acceptance of our cookie message, these cookies are seen as essential to the running of the website, without them, desktop, mobile and tablet devices will not display the images properly.

The following table lists any cookies that are seen as non-essential to the workings of the website.
